<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music on wooly mammoth&#39;s mighty absence</title>
    <link>/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music on wooly mammoth&#39;s mighty absence</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 22:27:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/music/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yo La Tengo - Painful</title>
      <link>/posts/yo-la-tengo-painful/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 22:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/yo-la-tengo-painful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-is-something-i-wrote-on-an-old-website-as-part-of-a-series-on-favorite-records-its-several-years-old-now-have-some-mid-late-2000s-style-music-blogging-its-killing-me-not-to-edit-any-of-it-but-its-a-time-capsule-from-the-vault&#34;&gt;This is something I wrote on an old website as part of a series on favorite records. It&#39;s several years old now. Have some mid-late 2000s style music blogging. It&#39;s killing me not to edit any of it, but... it&#39;s a time capsule. From the vault.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to Lungfish, Yo La Tengo is a band with a huge and flawless discography. They&#39;ve released well over a dozen LPs and probably a bazillion other things over their decades long career in music. They are a band unafraid to experiment with different styles of music and even how they &lt;a href=&#34;http://pitchfork.com/news/40594-yo-la-tengo-plan-insane-concept-tour/&#34;&gt;perform live&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like with Lungfish, I don&#39;t know what the consensus &amp;quot;best&amp;quot; Yo La Tengo record is. This series isn&#39;t about the &amp;quot;best,&amp;quot; right, but the albums that mean the most to me. That instantly makes Yo La Tengo&#39;s &lt;em&gt;Painful&lt;/em&gt; the go-to choice here. &lt;em&gt;Painful&lt;/em&gt; is one of their more consistent -- in overall sound -- records. Others, like &lt;em&gt;I Can Hear the Heart Beating As One&lt;/em&gt;, explore a lot of different styles of music in one place. &lt;em&gt;Painful&lt;/em&gt; is consistent and lets you slip into its world completely. You, as a listener, are allowed to spend 49 minutes in a very predictable, in a good way, atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
