<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fog series on wooly mammoth&#39;s mighty absence</title>
    <link>/tags/fog-series/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fog series on wooly mammoth&#39;s mighty absence</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 21:56:05 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/fog-series/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to See Through Fog: A Project</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-see-through-fog-a-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 21:56:05 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-see-through-fog-a-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.absentmammoth.org&#34;&gt;https://www.absentmammoth.org&lt;/a&gt; began in a much different form all the way back in January. Getting it to where it is today took dozens of hours and occupied most of my free time for several months. Making this website gave me something positive to focus on and has been a sick learning experience. I pushed myself more while working on it than I have with anything else in ages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to See Through Fog: Persona 5 Royal</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-see-through-fog-persona-5-royal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 23:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-see-through-fog-persona-5-royal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;listen-up-inmate-consider-this-sentence-a-major-spoiler-warning-if-you-care-about-that-kind-of-stuff&#34;&gt;Listen up, inmate! (Consider this sentence a major spoiler warning, if you care about that kind of stuff.)&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Persona 5 Royal&lt;/em&gt; is the best Japanese roleplaying game that isn’t &lt;em&gt;Tactics Ogre&lt;/em&gt;.  Recently released as an expanded take on the now few years’ old &lt;em&gt;Persona 5&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Royal&lt;/em&gt; furthers the story of a gang of outcast Japanese teens, each wronged in a different way by an adult or society. While ultimately a criticism of Japan, from the Lost Decade to Fukushima to today’s right-wing Abe government, the specifics of what it is condemning — corruption, selfishness, complicity, cruelty, sexism, and mindless obedience — are… well, baby, they’re universal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to See Through Fog: Hollywood Handbook</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-see-through-fog-hollywood-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-see-through-fog-hollywood-handbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;thanks-this-helped&#34;&gt;Thanks. This helped.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things aren&#39;t so hot these days, and there are lots of reasons to be anxious, mad, and depressed. I could enumerate them here, but anyone reading this already knows what&#39;s up. Instead, I&#39;d like to do a little series on things that have been helping me &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6JKgXdArpV8&#34;&gt;See Through Fog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.earwolf.com/show/hollywood-handbook/&#34;&gt;Hollywood Handbook&lt;/a&gt;, a podcast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
