<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wooly mammoth&#39;s mighty absence</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on wooly mammoth&#39;s mighty absence</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 21:25:07 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2022, apr</title>
      <link>/monthly-lists/2022-apr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 21:25:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/monthly-lists/2022-apr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Articles, games, music, podcasts from April, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022, mar</title>
      <link>/monthly-lists/2022-mar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:16:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/monthly-lists/2022-mar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;March&#39;s list has articles, games, music, and... more?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022, feb</title>
      <link>/monthly-lists/2022-feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 23:06:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/monthly-lists/2022-feb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;February&#39;s list has music, articles, podcasts, and games.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>video game art</title>
      <link>/posts/video-game-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 23:02:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/video-game-art/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several opinions about game design are offered by various people in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newyorker.com/books/under-review/sid-meier-and-the-meaning-of-civilization&#34;&gt;recent piece in &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; profiling famous video game guy Sid Meier. The article is worth the read even if you have never played one of Meier&#39;s games, but many of the opinions in it are things I believe the exact opposite of. The perspective it offers is cohesive and consistent, which is not always the case with games writing and having all of these ideas in one place makes them easier to dissect. Also, I love &lt;em&gt;Civilization,&lt;/em&gt; so I am appreciative of the fact that a guy of Meier&#39;s age and with his interest in niche strategy games, a genre that often attracts some of the most annoying people ever, is not offering up much worse thoughts here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>annoying guy music</title>
      <link>/posts/annoying-guy-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 22:41:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/annoying-guy-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s Taking Up Space, and then there&#39;s being a band called Viagra Boys.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>goods, 2020</title>
      <link>/posts/goods-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 23:27:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/goods-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Things I saw, listened to, read, or otherwise happened to me in 2020. Well, the things I liked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to See Through Fog: A Project</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-see-through-fog-a-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 21:56:05 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-see-through-fog-a-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.absentmammoth.org&#34;&gt;https://www.absentmammoth.org&lt;/a&gt; began in a much different form all the way back in January. Getting it to where it is today took dozens of hours and occupied most of my free time for several months. Making this website gave me something positive to focus on and has been a sick learning experience. I pushed myself more while working on it than I have with anything else in ages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>self-Deprecation</title>
      <link>/posts/self-deprecation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 22:52:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/self-deprecation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;
    ol {margin-bottom: .8rem;
    }
    &lt;/style&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a post about self-deprecation. This is me thinking through thoughts. It is a &#39;web log.&#39;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yo La Tengo - Painful</title>
      <link>/posts/yo-la-tengo-painful/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 22:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/yo-la-tengo-painful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-is-something-i-wrote-on-an-old-website-as-part-of-a-series-on-favorite-records-its-several-years-old-now-have-some-mid-late-2000s-style-music-blogging-its-killing-me-not-to-edit-any-of-it-but-its-a-time-capsule-from-the-vault&#34;&gt;This is something I wrote on an old website as part of a series on favorite records. It&#39;s several years old now. Have some mid-late 2000s style music blogging. It&#39;s killing me not to edit any of it, but... it&#39;s a time capsule. From the vault.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to Lungfish, Yo La Tengo is a band with a huge and flawless discography. They&#39;ve released well over a dozen LPs and probably a bazillion other things over their decades long career in music. They are a band unafraid to experiment with different styles of music and even how they &lt;a href=&#34;http://pitchfork.com/news/40594-yo-la-tengo-plan-insane-concept-tour/&#34;&gt;perform live&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like with Lungfish, I don&#39;t know what the consensus &amp;quot;best&amp;quot; Yo La Tengo record is. This series isn&#39;t about the &amp;quot;best,&amp;quot; right, but the albums that mean the most to me. That instantly makes Yo La Tengo&#39;s &lt;em&gt;Painful&lt;/em&gt; the go-to choice here. &lt;em&gt;Painful&lt;/em&gt; is one of their more consistent -- in overall sound -- records. Others, like &lt;em&gt;I Can Hear the Heart Beating As One&lt;/em&gt;, explore a lot of different styles of music in one place. &lt;em&gt;Painful&lt;/em&gt; is consistent and lets you slip into its world completely. You, as a listener, are allowed to spend 49 minutes in a very predictable, in a good way, atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>site changes &amp; updates</title>
      <link>/posts/site-changes-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 22:11:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/site-changes-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have made additions and adjustments to the site in a few places. Why?! Well,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to See Through Fog: Persona 5 Royal</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-see-through-fog-persona-5-royal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 23:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-see-through-fog-persona-5-royal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;listen-up-inmate-consider-this-sentence-a-major-spoiler-warning-if-you-care-about-that-kind-of-stuff&#34;&gt;Listen up, inmate! (Consider this sentence a major spoiler warning, if you care about that kind of stuff.)&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Persona 5 Royal&lt;/em&gt; is the best Japanese roleplaying game that isn’t &lt;em&gt;Tactics Ogre&lt;/em&gt;.  Recently released as an expanded take on the now few years’ old &lt;em&gt;Persona 5&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Royal&lt;/em&gt; furthers the story of a gang of outcast Japanese teens, each wronged in a different way by an adult or society. While ultimately a criticism of Japan, from the Lost Decade to Fukushima to today’s right-wing Abe government, the specifics of what it is condemning — corruption, selfishness, complicity, cruelty, sexism, and mindless obedience — are… well, baby, they’re universal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to See Through Fog: Hollywood Handbook</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-see-through-fog-hollywood-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-see-through-fog-hollywood-handbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;thanks-this-helped&#34;&gt;Thanks. This helped.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things aren&#39;t so hot these days, and there are lots of reasons to be anxious, mad, and depressed. I could enumerate them here, but anyone reading this already knows what&#39;s up. Instead, I&#39;d like to do a little series on things that have been helping me &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6JKgXdArpV8&#34;&gt;See Through Fog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.earwolf.com/show/hollywood-handbook/&#34;&gt;Hollywood Handbook&lt;/a&gt;, a podcast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>additional thanks to</title>
      <link>/additional-thanks-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 20:01:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/additional-thanks-to/</guid>
      <description>Hank Ewbank, for the cute lil shadow puppet mammoth display picture, as well as for showing me... Matthew Butterick&#39;s practicaltypography.com1 Though I have rewritten the css from scratch, Jamie Tanna&#39;s Hugo theme was source of the original theme. Dissecting his site is how I learned almost everything I have used to write the actual css/html of Absent Mammoth. I still look at his newer site&#39;s code to better understand how Hugo works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>/now</title>
      <link>/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 20:13:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/now/</guid>
      <description>article img:first-of-type { height: 3rem; width: auto; margin: -.7rem auto 1.4rem; } article img:not(:first-of-type) { height: 3rem; width: auto; margin: .7rem auto 1.4rem; }  february 28th, 2022: i&#39;ve rewritten the css/html of the site so that it is now, i think, all mine! i&#39;ve put this off for ages, having started it early last year and then put it on hold for several months. but it&#39;s now new from the ground up, using grid for the layout and with some changes to how the html partials for the site are setup.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
